SUNIL VEMURI: 嗨, 我是SUNIL VEMURI,
SUNIL VEMURI: Hi,
I'm Sunil Vemuri,
我已经等不及去享受
and I can't wait
for the day when
像电影里的人那样与自己的手表和手机交谈的那一天了.
I can talk to my watch and phone
like they do in the movies.
虽然我们离这还有一段距离.
We're still a ways
away from that.
但好消息是在Android M中
But the good news is we're
introducing a new API
我们引进了一个全新的接口, 以让我们朝向这个方向
in Android M that takes
us an important step
迈出重要的一步.
in that direction.
它就是语音交互接口,
It's called voice
interaction API,
它让应用与用户之间进行口语化交谈.
and it lets apps have
spoken dialogues with users.
我喜欢在上下班的路上收听电台,
I love listening to the
radio on my commute,
应用TuneIn给予了我丰富的选择.
and the TuneIn app
gives me great choices.
OK Google, 在TuneIn上播放音乐.
OK Google, play music on TuneIn.
谷歌应用助手: 哪一种流派
GOOGLE APP ASSISTANT:
Which genre would you
你想要收听?
like to listen to?
SUNIL VEMURI: 古典.
SUNIL VEMURI: Classical.
谷歌应用助手: 播放古典音乐.
GOOGLE APP ASSISTANT:
Playing classical.
SUNIL VEMURI: 处理语音输入可能会很复杂.
SUNIL VEMURI: Handling
voice input can be complex.
此外, 我不只是给出了一个指令.
Also I didn't just
give a command.
我们进行了交谈, 并且TuneIn向我提出了一个问题.
I had a conversation where
TuneIn asked me a question.
这样的交谈才是新的特性所在.
That conversation
part is what's new.
我的同事Barnaby和我将向你展示语音指令,
My colleague Barnaby and I will
show you how voice actions,
以及语音交互接口,
together with the
voice interaction API,
怎样使像TuneIn这样的语音交谈功能
make it possible for you to
build conversational voice
成为可能.
experiences like TuneIn's.
让我们先看一个简单的系统概述.
Let's first look at a
brief system overview.
说出"OK Google"开启交互, 而它又被称作是热词.
It starts with "OK Google"
also known as the hot word.
这样便触发了谷歌应用助手.
That triggers the assistant,
in this case, the Google App.
应用助手开始监听用户.
It starts listening to the user.
语音文本, 基于云端的自然语言
The speech-to-text,
cloud-based natural language,
以及Google知识图谱共同决定了
and Knowledge
Graph work together
应用应该完成什么样的事情.
to determine what
should be done.
如果它是一个指令, 它会触发Android系统上的一个意图.
If it's an action, an
Android intent is triggered.
在我们刚才举的例子中, 这样的意图将由TuneIn来处理.
In our example, the intent
is handled by TuneIn.
现在, Barnaby将告诉你如何在你的应用中实现此功能.
Now Barnaby will tell you
how to do this in your app.
BARNABY JAMES: 嗨, 我是Barnaby James,
BARNABY JAMES: Hi,
I'm Barnaby James,
我是谷歌Voice Actions团队的一员.
and I work on the Voice
Actions team at Google.
对于某些语音指令, 应用该做些什么是明确的.
For some voice actions, it's
clear what an app should do.
但如果用户的指令不明确,
What if the user's
command isn't clear,
并且你的应用不知道要做些什么,
and your app isn't
sure what to do,
并想询问用户一个问题?
and wants to ask
the user a question?
或者可能它需要确认这么做是否正确.
Or maybe it needs to
confirm something is safe.
语音交互接口让你的应用专注于
The Voice Interaction API lets
your app focus on the questions
向用户提问的问题, 而谷歌应用助手会处理
to ask the user
while Google handles
语音文本, 麦克风的设置, 以及分析
the speech-to-text,
microphone setup, and parsing
用户的答复.
the responses.
设想你的应用想要在播放媒体前
Suppose your app wanted
to confirm with the user
向用户确认是否继续播放
before playing something
that may not be
可能不适合未成年人的内容.
suitable for younger listeners.
你可以调用语音交互函数
You would call the
voice interactor
并提交一个确认请求,
and submit a request
for a confirmation
以及你的提示.
along with your prompt.
谷歌应用助手可以辨认许多表示确认的方式
Google recognizes many
of the common ways
比如人们经常说的"是的",
people give a
confirmation such as yes,
"请这么做", "继续"或者"就是这样".
please do it, go
ahead, or make it so.
或者如果你希望用户像TuneIn那样
Or if you wanted to ask the
user to pick from a list
在一个列表中选择, 你可以在你提交语音交互请求时
like TuneIn did, you'd
create an array of options
创建一个存放选项的数组.
when you submit the voice
interaction request.
如果用户说出了不存在列表中的选项,
If your user speaks
something not on the list,
谷歌应用助手会再次提醒你.
Google will take care
of reprompting for you.
OK Google, 回到Sunil那儿.
OK Google, back to Sunil.
SUNIL VEMURI: 谢谢Barnaby.
SUNIL VEMURI: Thanks, Barnaby.
我们还忘记了一件重要的事情.
There's one important
thing we left out.
用户是如何使用语音来打开应用的?
How does a user launch
your app by voice?
对于用户在日常中涉及到声音的许多事情,
For many of the common
things users do with voice,
例如搜索, 播放音乐, 设置闹钟
such as searching, playing
music, setting alarms,
等等, 你应该使用系统语音指令.
and so on, you should
use system voice actions.
谷歌应用助手能够识别用户发出的这些指令
Google recognizes when
a user asks for these
并且触发其中的意图.
and fires the intent.
这是TuneIn所使用到的功能,
This is what TuneIn
used, and these
而这些都在我们的网站上有相关文档.
are documented on our website.
你现在就可以使用这些功能,
You can use these
right away, and we're
并且我们会一直增加更多的内容.
adding more all the time.
如果系统指令不能满足你的应用需求,
If system actions
don't fit your app,
我们最近引入了自定义指令.
we recently introduced
custom actions.
举个例子, 你可以说, "OK Google, 用Shazam播放这首歌."
For example, I can say, "OK
Google, Shazam this song."
你可以访问这个地址学习自定义语音指令的更多内容.
Here's the URL to learn more
about Custom Voice Sections.
语音交互功能是提高应用下载量
Voice is a great way to
drive traffic to your app
以及吸引用户的一个很棒的方式.
and engage users.
那么, 访问我们的CodeLab, 尝试一下语音交互的功能吧.
Next, check out our CodeLab
and try out voice interaction.
谢谢, 下次见.
Thanks and see you next time.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]